Guide to the John Ferguson Weir Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John Ferguson Weir papers
1838-1957
1861-1928
MS 550
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12
Correspondence, addresses and writings, papers relating to the Yale School of the Fine Arts, and other papers of John F. Weir, artist, painter and first director of the Yale School of the Fine Arts, serving from 1869-1913. Correspondents include many persons prominent in the art world between 1870 and 1920. There is also much material on the origins and development of art education in this country and at Yale.
Weir, John F. (John Ferguson), 1841-1926
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. James DeWolf Perry, 1939; gift of DeWolf Perry, 1977; transferred from departmental publications, 2002.
Arrangement
Arranged in five series and two additions: I. Correspondence. II. Addresses and Writings. III. Papers, Plans, and Notes: Yale School of the Fine Arts. IV. Personal Papers and Memorabilia. V. Bicentennial Art Exhibition.
Biographical / Historical
John Ferguson Weir was born at West Point, New York in 1841. The son of the well-known artist Robert Walter Weir, he achieved fame as a painter early, and in 1869 was appointed the first Director of the new Yale School of the Fine Arts. Starting with little more than a new building and a slim endowment, Weir developed the School into a highly respected and well-known institution.
In many ways, the Yale School of the Fine Arts was a pioneer. It was the first American art school connected with an institution of higher learning. It was the first School at Yale to admit women. And Weir and Yale were prominent in efforts to establish courses in the art and science of architecture.
Although his duties as Director of the Yale School of the Fine Arts occupied much of his time, Weir continued to paint throughout his life. He also lectured on art and related subjects and published many articles in both scholarly and popular journals. A deeply religious man, Weir wrote three books on religion and mysticism. After guiding the Art School for forty-four years, Weir retired in 1913. He died thirteen years later in his 85th year.
Scope and Contents
The John Ferguson Weir Papers contain many letters from persons prominent in the art world from the 1870s to the 1920s and a wealth of information about Weir's own life and beliefs. There is also material on the origin and development of art education in the United States and at Yale. Researchers interested in this aspect of the Weir Papers should also consult the Archives of the Yale School of the Fine Arts, located in Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
The John Ferguson Weir Papers are divided into four series: I. CORRESPONDENCE; II. ADDRESSES AND WRITINGS; III. PAPERS, PLANS, AND NOTES RE: YALE SCHOOL OF FINE ARTS; IV. PERSONAL PAPERS AND MEMORABILIA.
The CORRESPONDENCE series contains both Weir's personal and professional correspondence. He was familiar with most of the prominent artists and architects of his time, and as Director of the School of the Fine Arts, he frequently invited famous artists to lecture at Yale. This correspondence tends to be brief and businesslike. Some of the personal correspondence, however, is more expansive. Among the correspondents are: John W. Alexander (15 items), Charles Henry Caffin (11 items), John Merven Carrere (9 items), Kenyon Cox (10 items), Frank Miles Day (6 items), Sanford Robinson Gifford (26 items), William Henry Goodyear (14 items), James Mason Hoppin (14 items), Jervis McEntee (3 items), Donald Grant Mitchell (9 items), Frederic Remington (4 items), Paul Sabatier (1 item), Truman Seymour (8 items), Launt Thompson (3 items), and Peter Bonnett Wight (3 items). Filed at the end of this section are two folders of Mrs. Mary French Weir's correspondence and a folder of letters of Weir's daughter, Edith Weir Perry.
The second series, ADDRESSES AND WRITINGS, contains articles, lectures, and speeches by Weir. Included is a copy of Weir's partially completed memoirs. Some of the addresses and writings are in manuscript form; others have been printed.
The third series, PAPERS, PLANS, AND NOTES RE: YALE SCHOOL OF FINE ARTS, contains material relating to Weir's activities as Director of the School. This includes notes on the founding and organization of the School and on the development of the curriculum. There is also material on School finances, scholarships, and the like. Most of this material consists of notes or drafts of proposals in Weir's own hand. Also filed in this section are exhibition programs and lecture syllabi from the Yale School of the Fine Arts.
The fourth series, PERSONAL PAPERS AND MEMORABILIA, contains a wide variety of material relating to Weir's personal life, including several diaries and sketchbooks. In addition there are newspaper clippings collected by Weir, including reviews of his own books. There are also numerous photographs of Weir and his family and a folder of notes and writings by Mary French Weir.
Note: Additional Weir papers are in the possession of Rev. DeWolf Perry of Princeton, Massachusetts.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Art -- Study and teaching; Art; Artists; Educators; Painters; Alexander, John White, 1856-1915; Atterbury, Grosvenor, 1869-1956; Baldwin, Simeon E. (Simeon Eben), 1840-1927; Blashfield, Edwin Howland, 1848-1936; Brush, George Jarvis, 1831-1912; Caffin, Charles H. (Charles Henry), 1854-1918; Carrère, John Merven, 1858-1911; Cesnola, Luigi Palma di, 1832-1904; Chase, William Merritt, 1849-1916; Chittenden, R. H. (Russell Henry), 1856-1943; Clarke, Caspar Purdon, Sir, 1846-1911; Coffin, William A. (William Anderson), 1855-1925; Cook, Albert S. (Albert Stanburrough), 1853-1927; Cook, Clarence, 1828-1900; Cook, Walter, 1846-1916; Cortissoz, Royal, 1869-1948; Cox, Kenyon, 1856-1919; Dana, Edward Salisbury, 1849-1935; Day, Frank Miles, 1861-1918; Day, George Parmly, 1876-1959; Delano, William Adams, 1874-1960; Dexter, Franklin Bowditch, 1842-1920; Dwight, Timothy, 1828-1916; East, Alfred, Sir, 1844-1913; Eaton, D. Cady (Daniel Cady), 1837-1912; Eliot, Charles William, 1834-1926; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers), 1883-1950; Farnam, Henry W. (Henry Walcott), 1853-1933; Farnam, William Whitman, 1844-1929; Fisher, George Park, 1827-1909; Fisher, Irving, 1867-1947; French, Daniel Chester, 1850-1931; Frothingham, Arthur L., Jr. (Arthur Lincoln), 1859-1923; Gifford, Sanford Robinson, 1823-1880; Gilbert, Cass, 1859-1934; Gilman, Daniel C. (Daniel Coit), 1831-1908; Godwin, Parke, 1816-1904; Goodyear, W. H. (William Henry), 1846-1923; Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930; Hamlin, A. D. F. (Alfred Dwight Foster), 1855-1926; Hastings, Thomas, 1860-1929; Hawthorne, Charles Webster, 1872-1930; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878; Homer, Winslow, 1836-1910; Hoppin, J. M. (James Mason), 1820-1906; Hunt, Richard Morris, 1827-1895; Huntington, Daniel, 1816-1906; Isham, Samuel, 1855-1914; Jesup, Morris K. (Morris Ketchum), 1830-1908; Johnson, Eastman, 1824-1906; Jones, Frederick Scheetz, 1862-1944; Kendall, William Sergeant, 1869-1938; Keppel, Frederick P. (Frederick Paul), 1875-1943; La Farge, Bancel, 1865-1938; La Farge, John, 1835-1910; Langzettel, George Henry, d. 1953; Longfellow, William P. P. (William Pitt Preble), 1836-1913; Low, Will Hicok, 1853-1932; Mansfield, Burton, 1856-1932; Marquand, Henry Gurdon, 1819-1902; Marshall, Henry Rutgers, 1852-1927; McEntee, Jervis, 1828-1891; McKim, Charles Follen, 1847-1909; Metcalf, Willard Leroy, 1858-1925; Millet, Francis Davis, 1846-1912; Mitchell, Donald Grant, 1822-1908; Mosler, Henry, 1841-1920; Mowbray, H. Siddons (Harry Siddons), 1858-1928; Munger, Theodore T. (Theodore Thornton), 1830-1910; Niemeyer, John Henry, 1839-1932; Norton, Charles Eliot, 1827-1908; Olmsted, Frederick Law, 1870-1957; Parker, Horatio W. (Horatio William), 1863-1919; Partridge, William Ordway, 1861-1930; Perkins, Charles C. (Charles Callahan), 1823-1886; Perrin, Bernadotte, 1847-1920; Phelps, Edward John, 1822-1900; Pierrepont, Edwards, 1817-1892; Porter, Noah, 1811-1892; Pyle, Howard, 1853-1911; Raymond, John H. (John Howard), 1814-1878; Remington, Frederic, 1861-1909; Sabatier, Paul, 1858-1928; Salisbury, Edward Elbridge, 1814-1901; Sanders, Frank Knight, 1861-1933; Seelye, Laurenus Clark, 1837-1924; Seymour, George Dudley, 1859-1945; Seymour, Thomas D. (Thomas Day), 1848-1907; Seymour, Truman, 1824-1891; Shirlaw, Walter, 1838-1909; Simmons, Edward, 1852-1931; Smillie, James David, 1833-1909; Smith, Francis Hopkinson, 1838-1915; Stedman, Edmund Clarence, 1833-1908; Stoeckel, Carl, 1858-1925; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958; Street, Augustus Russell, 1791-1866; Sturgis, Russell, 1836-1909; Sumner, William Graham, 1840-1910; Taft, Lorado, 1860-1936; Thompson, Launt, 1833-1894; Twachtman, John Henry, 1853-1902; Tyler, Morris Franklin, 1848-1907; Van Dyke, John Charles, 1856-1932; Vinton, Frederick Porter, 1846-1911; Walker, John Brisben, 1847-1931; Ware, William R. (William Robert), 1832-1915; Watrous, George Dutton, 1858-1940; Weir, John F. (John Ferguson), 1841-1926; Weir, Julian Alden, 1852-1919; Weir, Robert Walter, 1803-1889; Whittredge, Worthington, 1820-1910; Wight, P. B. (Peter Bonnett), 1838-1925; Wolf, Henry, 1852-1916; Woolsey, Theodore Salisbury, 1852-1929; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. School of Fine Arts
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1861-1928, 1939; Series I; 2.5; (5 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Letters received are arranged alphabetically by name of writer. Letters written by Weir are filed under the name of the addressee. Correspondence of Weir's wife, Mary French Weir, and of his daughter, Edith Weir Perry, is placed at the end of this series.
  The number of items are contained in parentheses before the unitdate
  - Minor and General Correspondence
    - A (16), 1899, 1901-1902, 1907, 1911-1912, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B(8), 1890, 1892, 1901, 1912-1913, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - C(11), 1876, 1890, 1893, 1895-1896, 1898, 1901, 1911, 1915, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - D (22), 1869, 1880, 1886-1887, 1891, 1893, 1899, 1901, 1906-1908, 1910, 1912, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - E, F (8), 1895, 1901, 1908, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - G (10), 1874, 1876, 1894, 1901, 1912, 1916, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - H (22), 1870, 1881, 1883, 1889, 1893-1894, 1900-1901, 1903, 1907, 1909, 1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - J, K, L (15), 1874, 1901, 1907, 1909, 1911, 1912-1913, 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - M (16), 1901, 1906, 1909, 1911, 1913, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - N, O (12), 1901, 1904, 1908, 1910-1913, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - P (16), 1895, 1901, 1911, 1913, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - R (7), 1890, 1901, 1910, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - S (27), 1876, 1879, 1881, 1893, 1900-1901, 1904, 1907-1909, 1911-1913, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - T, V (13), 1889, 1896, 1899, 1901, 1903, 1909-1911, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - W (21), 1876, 1901, 1903, 1908-1909, 1910, 1912-1913, 1920, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Y, Z (10), 1873, 1876, 1898, 1901, 1907, 1911, 1913, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - unidentified, (6), 1882, 1894, 1901, 1905, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence (by Individual Name Folder)
    - Abbott, Lyman, (1), 1903 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Adams, Herbert, (3), 1894, 1899, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Alden, B. R. (13), 1869, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Alden, R. Percy, (2), 1904 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Alexander, John W. and Elizabeth A. (15), 1905, 1911, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - American Institute for Scientific Research, (1), 1916 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - D. Appleton and Co. (3), 1907 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - The Atlantic Monthly (3), 1917 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Atterbury, Grosvenor (4), 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Avery, Samuel P. (3), undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Bailey, William Whitman (3), 1908, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Baldwin, Simeon E. (1), 1891 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Barnard, Frederic (1), 1901 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Beckwith, J. Carroll (2), 1905, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bennett, Thomas G. (6), 1894, 1896, 1900, 1904, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Berwind, John E. (4), 1909 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bigelow, John (3), 1889, 1903, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Blashfield, Edwin H. (10), 1896, 1911-1913 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Boardman, F. C. (3), 1902, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - The Henry Bonnard Bronze Co. (8), 1895-1896, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Bosworth, F. Huntington, Jr. (1), 1907 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bragdon, Claude (2), 1911 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bristol, Stoddard, Beach and Fisher (9), 1908 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Brooks, Phillips (1), 1889 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Brown, Bolton C. (1), 1905 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Brown, John Appleton (2), undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Brush, George Jarvis (1), 1872 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Burnham, Daniel Hudson (1), 1907 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Burnham, William A. (1), undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Burr, Fannie C. (5), 1900-1901 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Burrell, David James (2), 1898-1899 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Caffin, Charles Henry (11), 1905, 1908-1909, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Carrère, John Merven (9), 1904, 1906-1907 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Carrington, J. B. (1), undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Carter, Franklin (1), 1904 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - The Century Co. (9), 1882, 1893-1894, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Cesnola, Luigi Palma di (7), 1878-1880, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Chandler, F. W. (1), 1904 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Chase, Elsie R. (2), 1901 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Chase, William Merritt (2), 1885-1886 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Chittenden, Russell H. (3), 1910-1912 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Clark, Thomas F. (1), 1901 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Clark, Thomas S. (1), 1908 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Clarke, Sir Caspar Purdon (2), 1905-1906 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Coffin, William A. (6), 1900-1901 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Colman, Samuel (1), 1905 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Cook, Albert Stanburrough (10), 1898-1900, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Cook, Clarence C. (4), 1878, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Cook, Walter (4), 1907 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Cortissoz, Royal (13), 1909 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Cowles, Edith V. and Genevieve A. (5), 1901 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Cox, Kenyon (10), 1904, 1906-1908, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Cram, Ralph Adams (8), 1906, 1909-1910, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Curtis, George W. (1), 1876 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Dana Edward S. (10), 1879, 1891, 1907-1910 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Day, Frank Miles (6), 1907 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Day, George Parmly (50), 1910-1913, 1918, 1925, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Dean, J. A. (6), 1868-1870 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Deidrickson, Theodore (4), 1910-1911 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Delano, Wm. Adams (2), undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Dewing, [Thomas W.?] (2), 1899 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Dexter, Franklin B. (19), 1871-1872, 1878-1889, 1882, 1894, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Durand, John (1), 1871 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Dwight, Timothy (20), 1887, 1889-1891, 1893, 1895-1896, 1898-1899, 1909-1910 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - East, Alfred (27), 1910-1913, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Eaton, D. Cady (4), 1902-1903 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Egan, Maurice F. (1), undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Ehrich, Louis R. (9), 1887, 1889, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Eliot, Charles W. (3), 1873, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Elliott, Huger (4), 1913, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - English, Henry F. (28), 1893-1894, 1899-1900, 1903-1904, 1909-1912 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Embree, Edwin Rogers
      General
      See: box 4, folder 115
    - Fairbanks, Arthur (3), 1923 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Farnam, Henry (2), 1875 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Farnam, Henry W. (2), 1912 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Farnam, William W. (11), 1895-1897, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Fisher, George P. (4), 1873, 1901, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Fisher, Irving (1), 1906 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Foote, Mary (6), 1897-1899 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - French, Daniel C. (3), 1910-1911 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - French, Mr. and Mrs. John W. (10), 1869, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - French, Sallie (1), 1869 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Frothingham, Arthur L. (4), 1899 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Garfield, Harry Augustus (1), 1913 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Gibson, C. D. (3), undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Gifford, Sanford Robinson (26), 1868, 1870-1871, 1873-1875, 1876-1877, 1879-1880, undated (Box 3, Folder 60a)
    - Gifford, Mrs. S. R. (3), 1880-1881 (Box 3, Folder 60b)
    - Gilbert, Cass (7), 1906-1907, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Gilman, Daniel Coit (3), 1871, 1897, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Godwin, Parke (2), 1876 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Goodyear, William Henry (14), 1899, 1902-1904, 1906-1909, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Grant, Percy S. (1), 1909 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Grant, Robert (1), undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Hadley, Arthur T. (35), 1899-1906 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Hadley, Arthur T. (61), 1908-1913, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Haight, Charles C. (26), 1904, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Hamlin, Alfred Dwight Foster (5), 1900-1901, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Harris, William Laurel (2), 1911 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Hartley, Jonathan S. (1), 1897 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Hartshorne, Robert (1), 1913 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Hastings, Thomas (4), 1905-1906 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Hawthorne, Charles W. (1), 1912 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Heaton, Clement (2), 1912 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Henry, Joseph (1), 1874 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Herkomer, Hubert (5), 1882-1883 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Hine, Francis Lyman (1), 1901 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Homer, Winslow (1), 1874 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Hooper, Franklin W. (5), 1899-1901 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Hoppin James Mason (13), 1872, 1880-1881, 1890, 1898, 1900-1901, 1903, 1905, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Hunt, Richard Morris (2), 1871, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Huntington, Daniel (3), 1869, 1871, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Isham, Samuel (2), 1901 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Ito, Soken (2), 1912, undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Jaccaci, August F. (18), 1894, 1897, 1903, 1911-1913 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Jesup, Morris K. (3), 1901 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Johnson, Eastman (3), 1870, 1884 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Jones, Frederick S. (12), 1910-1913 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Kelly, J. Frederick (1), 1916 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Kendall, William Sergeant (7), 1913, 1915, undated (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Kennedy, E. G. (1), 1901 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Keppel, Frederick (2), 1883, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Kirby, Thomas E. (1), 1899 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Kriehn, George (2), 1912-1913 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - LaFarge, Bancel (1), 1899 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - LaFarge, John (7), 1876, 1899, undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Langzettel, George H. (45), 1904, 1913-1915, 1918-1919, undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Lawrie, Lee (2), 1913, undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Longfellow, William Pitt Preble (3), 1877, 1882-1883 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Low, Will H. (6), 1899-1900, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Luguiens, Emma C. (1), 1906 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Luguiens, Huc M. (10), 1904-1906 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - McClung, Lee (23), 1907-1909 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - McEntee, Jervis (3), 1868-1869 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - McKim, Charles F. (2), 1904, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Mansfield, Burton (6), 1908, 1910-1912, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Mansfield, Howard (1), 1905 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Marquand, Allan (1), 1905 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Marquand, Henry G. (1), 1882 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Marshall, Henry Rutgers (6), 1899 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Mather, Frank Jewett (2), 1911, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Metcalf, Willard L. (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Millet, Francis D. (7), 1904, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Mitchell, Charles L. (3), 1880 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Mitchell, Donald Grant (9), 1876-1877, 1908, undated (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Moore, Frank G. (4), 1901 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Moses, Robert (2), 1909, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Mosler, Henry (1), 1910 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Mowbray, Henry Siddons (2), 1899, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Munger, Theodore Thornton (5), 1889, 1899, 1904, undated (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Niemeyer, John Henry (5), 1900, 1909, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Norton, Charles Eliot (6), 1876, 1878, undated (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Olmsted, Frederick Law, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Palmer, Charles Ray (7), 1901, 1903, 1906, undated (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Parker, Horatio W. (8), 1899, 1906, 1908, 1911-1912 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Partridge, William Ordway (2), 1901, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Paulding, G. (2), 1875 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Peck, Tracy (1), 1898 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Perkins, Charles Callahan (6), 1873, 1881, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Perrin, Bernadotte (4), 1895, 1900, 1904, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Perry, Edith Weir (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Pfeiffer, Carl (1), 1875 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Phelps, Edward J. (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Pierrepont, Edwards (1), 1880 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Pinchot, James W. (2), 1901 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Porter, Noah (4), 1872, 1875, 1878, 1880, 1882 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Pratt, Bela Lyon (5), 1901 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Princeton Review (5), 1881-1882 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Pyle, Howard (3), 1903, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Raymond, John Howard (5), 1875-1876 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Remington, Eve A. (2), 1910 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Remington, Frederic (4), undated (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Ross, Denman W. (3), 1902-1903 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Sabatier, Paul (1), 1903 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Salisbury, Edward Elbridge (17), 1867, 1870-1872, 1876-1879, undated (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Sanders, Frank K. (3), 1904, undated (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Schopper, Jean (1), 1899 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Seelye, Laurenus C. (2), 1876 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Seymour, George D. (5), 1907, 1910, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Seymour, Thomas Day (2), 1900, undated (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Seymour, Truman and Louisa Weir (9), 1868-1869, undated (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Shirlaw, Walter (1), 1898 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Simmons, Edward (1), 1899 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Smillie, James David (4), 1879-1880 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Smith, Francis Hopkinson (5), 1894, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Spaenkuch, August (4), 1907 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Stedman, Edmund C. (5), 1871, 1902, 1901, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Stoeckel, Carl (2), 1901, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, Jr. (47), 1900-1908 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, Jr. (39), 1909-1910 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, Jr. (39), 1911-1912 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, Jr. (29), 1913-1915, 1917, undated (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Street, Augustus R. (1), 1865 (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Street, Caroline M. (1), 1866 (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Sturgis, Russell (1), 1899 (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Sumner, William Graham (1), 1879 (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Taft, Lorado (3), 1906-1907 (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Thompson, Launt (3), 1869-1871 (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Trowbridge, Rutherford (34), 1899-1905, 1907, 1909, 1912, undated (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Twachtman, Alden (2), 1900-1901 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Twachtman, John Henry (8), 1900-1901 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Tyler, Morris F. (80), 1900, 1902-1904 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - University Club (6), 1888, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Van Dyke, John Charles (2), 1913, undated (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Vinton, Frederic Porter (3), 1901 (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Voorhees, Clark G. (2), 1901, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Vose, R. C. (3), 1919-1920 (Box 5, Folder 127)